

# ARIEL LARA PEDRAZA

Computer Systems Engineering Student

Cybersecurity

# PERSONAL INFORMATION

I'm a 22 years old Computer Systems Engineer Student at Instituto Tecnológico de Morelia in México, coursing my 9th semester. I'm working as a FullStack Developer at IINII and Stardeos (standby). I consider myself as a extremelly curious person and I'm always ready to give my best. Hoping to join an International Residences Program in order to keep learning, improve my skills and finalize my university.

I'm pretty calm, I love coffee, animals and music. I'm a Linux enthusiast and I'll work hard to get CEH certification as soon as possible.

#### **CONTACT INFO**

Email: drky@raccoonsolutions.net

GitHub: github.com/drky99
LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/drky
Portfolium: raccoonsolutions.net/drky

#### PERSONAL INTERESTS & HOBBIES

Cybersecurity, Probability & Statistics, Latte Art, Privacy, Crypto, Digital Drawing, Operative Systems, Low Level Programming, Electronics, Blockchain, Fintech, Distrotesting, Graphic Design, Videogames.

#### **APTITUDES**

Leadership, Teamwork, Effective Communication, Problem-Solving, Active Listening, Open-mindeness, Creativity, Critical thinking.

# **EDUCATION & COURSES**

INSTITUTO TECNOLÓGICO DE MÉXICO (2017-Today) I'm studying Computer Systems Engineering at the Instituto Tecnológico de México campus Morelia, I'm about to finish my 9th semester on the specialization of Cybersecurity.

#### CISCO NETACAD (2021)

- CCNA Routing and Switching: Basic principles of routing and switching
- CCNA Routing and Switching: Scaling Networks

# **SKILLS & TOOLS**

#### **HACKING TOOLS**

Nmap, Aircrack-ng, OpenVAS, Hashcat, Zphisher, Joomscan, Wireshark, Metasploit, Nessus, John The Reaper, Burpsuite Professional, Sherlock, Lynis.

## **SKILLS & TOOLS**

#### PROGRAMING LANGUAGES

Python, JavaScript, Java, C++, PHP, C#, C, Kotlin, SQL, Assembly, TypeScript.

#### OTHER TOOLS

VirtualBox, VMWare, Hyper-V, VMWare EXSI, Packet Tracer, Photoshop, Illustrator, Medibang, Krita, Gimp, Android Studio, Cinema 4D, Cheat Engine, Microsoft Office, TrueNas, Serverless, XenServer, OpenStack, Linux, MySQL, MariaDB, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Redis, Firebase, Docker, Apache, NodeJS, HTML, CSS, GIT, Android, Raspberry Pi, Arduino, React, React-Native, MaterializeCSS, Bootstrap, Ulkit CSS, JWT, Express, Svelte, Laravel, Socker.IO, Sequelize, Material Ul, Selenium, jQuery, WordPress,

#### LANGUAGES

- Spanish (Native Speaker)
- English (Advanced, C1)

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### **ABOUT CYBERSECURITY**

I have worked on many academic projects related. These activities include cisco routers and switches configuration, Mikrotiks and Iptables firewall configuration, Information Security Management System (ISMS) plannning and configuration, Cloud computing based tools configuration, network scanning practices, penetration testing practices, hardening practices, unidirectional and bidirectional encryption practices.

#### DIINCO (2022-Today)

I'm working as a FullStack developer at DIINCO,a webbased platform for remote project management. Also, I do the Team Leader role on this project.

#### Stardeos (2022-Today)

I've been working as volunteer colaborator at Stardeos for a short period of time. On this project I've made optimization and security contributions. Also, I've worked as FullStack developer on this project.

## El Tepetate (2019-2020)

As project for the Academic Software Factory of the Instituto Tecnológico de Morelia, my team and me made a web technologies based administration platform for the trout farm El Tepetate.

#### Administrative Enginieering Master (2021)

As social service project, my classmate and me, made the presentation web page for the Administrative Engineering Master at the Instituto Tecnológico de Morelia.